Finding Aid for the Lejaren Hiller Collection of Audio Tape Recordings, 1958-1985
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Portfolio, for diverse performers and tapes (1974) (H. 51), undated, 1 10 inch reel; 15 ips (38 cm/sec.), 2-channel stereo., Tail out; Master tape Master combination tape "Combination of tapes 1 and 4 for making four-channel master." Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 176)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Portfolio, for diverse performers and tapes (1974) (H. 51), undated, 1 10 inch reel; 15 ips (38 cm/sec.), 2-channel stereo., Tail out; Stereo Master Stereo master "Tapes 2 and 3 combined for 4-channel master - intermediate tape." Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 177)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Portfolio, for diverse performers and tapes (1974) (H. 51), Concert performances of March 21 and June 9, 1976, 1 10 inch reel; 7 ½ ips, 2-channel stereo.; Master tapes Master performance tape Performers: Members of the Center of the Creative and Performing Arts conducted by Jan Williams. Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 178)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Portfolio, for diverse performers and tapes (1974) (H. 51), Recorded October 1978, 1 10 inch reel; 15 ips, 2-channel stereo., Dolby A301 stretched, tail out; Master tape Master performance tape, solo violoncello version Performers: Frances-Marie Uitti, cello Solo cello version. Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 179)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Portfolio, for diverse performers and tapes (1974) (H. 51), undated, 1 10 inch reel; speed unknown"Dolby A, etc",; Disk Submaster Submaster copy of Tape 179 Cello solo version Tape digitally reformatted: No (Item 180)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Portfolio, for diverse performers and tapes (1974) (H. 51), undated, 1 10 inch reel; 7 ½ ips, 2-channel stereo., Tail out; Submaster "Vocal version" Vocal version "Take 3: preferred version; Take 4: voices only" Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 181)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Malta, for tuba and tape (1975) (H. 52), undated, 1 7 inch reel; 7 ½ ips, stereo (½ track); Duplicate of Tape 183 Electronic tape part published by Theodore Presser, 1976. Tape digitally reformatted: No (Item 182)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Malta, for tuba and tape (1975) (H. 52), undated, 1 7 inch reel; 7 ½ ips, stereo (½ track); T. Presser tape issued with score Electronic tape part published by Theodore Presser, 1976. Tape digitally reformatted: No (Item 183)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Malta, for tuba and tape (1975) (H. 52), undated, 1 7 inch reel; 7 ½ ips, 2-channel stereo., Tail out; Cue tape Duplicate of Tape 187 Cue 1 - 1st movement; Cue 2 - 2nd movement; Cue 3 - 3rd movement; Cue 4 - 4th movement Tape digitally reformatted: No (Item 184)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Malta, for tuba and tape (1975) (H. 52), Recorded April 1 and 3, 1977, 1 7 inch reel; 7 ½ ips, 2-channel stereo.; Duplicate of Tape 186 Performers: Barton Cummings, tuba Duration: 21:12 Tape digitally reformatted: No (Item 185)
  I. Geographical 5:18 II. Historical 5:09 III. Carnival 5:04 IV. Personal 5:32
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Malta, for tuba and tape (1975) (H. 52), Recorded April 1 and 3, 1977, 1 10 inch reel; 15 ips, 2-channel stereo., Tail out; Master tape Master performance tape Performers: Barton Cummings, tuba Duration: 21:12 Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 186)
  I. Geographical 5:15 II. Historical 5:08 III. Carnival 5:02 IV. Personal 5:35
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Malta, for tuba and tape (1975) (H. 52), undated, 1 10 inch reel; 15 ips, 2-channel stereo., Tail out; Cue tape master Master cue tapes Duration: 21:18 Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 187)
  I. First Movement 5:15 II. Second Movement 5:08 III. Third Movement 5:02 IV. Fourth Movement 5:35 Leader 0:18
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Malta, for tuba and tape (1975) (H. 52), undated, 1 10 inch reel; 15 ips, 2-channel stereo., Tail out; Cue tapes Duplicate of Tapes 187 and 225 Duration: 21:18 (H. 52); ca. 8:00 (H. 62) Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 188)
  I. First Movement 5:15 II. Second Movement 5:08 III. Third Movement 5:03 IV. Fourth Movement 5:35
  H. 62, Quadrilateral, for piano and tape (1981) I. Prelude 1:36 II. Interlude I 1:36 III. Interlude II 1:36 IV. Interlude III 1:36 V. Postlude 1:36
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Preview of coming attractions, for symphony orchestra (1975) (H. 53), Complete version recorded August 31, 1987, 1 7 inch reel; 7 ½ ips, full-track mono.; Only tape Performers: Complete version: Sao Paulo State Symphony Orchestra conducted by John Boudler; Abridged version: Buffalo Philharmonic Orchestra conducted by Michael Tilson Thomas Duration: 15:34 (complete version) Complete and abridged versions Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 189)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Electronic sonata, for four-channel tape (1976) (H. 54), undated, 1 7 inch reel; 7 ½ ips, 2-channel stereo., Tail out; Duplicate of Tape 194 Duration: 53:00 (total) "2-channel version" Part One: Introduction, Exposition, Development; 32:56 Tape digitally reformatted: No (Item 190)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Electronic sonata, for four-channel tape (1976) (H. 54), undated, 1 7 inch reel; 7 ½ ips, 2-channel stereo., Tail out; Duplicate of Tape 195 Duration: 53:00 (total) "2-channel version" Part Two: Recapitulation, Coda; 20:04 Tape digitally reformatted: No (Item 191)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Electronic sonata, for four-channel tape (1976) (H. 54), undated, 1 10 inch reel; 15 ips, 4 channel quadraphonic, Tail out; Master tape Master quadraphonic Part One: Introduction, Exposition, Development; 32:56; "Also: Calibration tape on front." Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 192)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Electronic sonata, for four-channel tape (1976) (H. 54), undated, 1 10 inch reel; 15 ips, 4 channel quadraphonic, Tail out; Master tape Master quadraphonic Part Two: Recapitulation, Coda; 20:04 Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 193)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Electronic sonata, for four-channel tape (1976) (H. 54), undated, 1 10 inch reel; 15 ips, 2-channel stereo., Tail out; Master tape Master 2-channel tape "2-channel version" Part A: Introduction, Exposition; 12:36; "Test tone on front" Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 194)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Electronic sonata, for four-channel tape (1976) (H. 54), undated, 1 10 inch reel; 15 ips, 2-channel stereo., Tail out; Master tape Master 2-channel tape "2-channel version" Part C: Recapitulation, Coda; 20:04 Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 195)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Electronic sonata, for four-channel tape (1976) (H. 54), undated, 1 10 inch reel; 7 ½ ips, 4 channel quadraphonic, 1 ½ mil tape; Tail out; Sub-master; Performance tape Submaster, quadraphonic performance tape Duration: 53:00 "Test tone on front of tape - Composition begins after green leader tape." Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 196)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Electronic sonata, for four-channel tape (1976) (H. 54), undated, 1 10 inch reel; 7 ½ ips; Performance copy Performance copy, 2-channel? Duration: 53:00 Tape digitally reformatted: No (Item 197)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Electronic sonata, for four-channel tape (1976) (H. 54), undated, 1 10 inch reel; 19 cm/sec.; Tail out, 4 channel quadraphonic, DBX, 1/4 in. tape; Performance tape DBX encoded "DBX-encoded version" Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 198)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Electronic sonata, for four-channel tape (1976) (H. 54), undated, 1 10 inch reel; 19 cm/sec., 4 channel quadraphonic, DBX, 1/4 in. tape; Tail out; Performance tape Looks like duplicate of Tape 198, but make sure it isn't Part II with Tape 198 being Part I "DBX-encoded version" Tape digitally reformatted: No (Item 199)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Electronic sonata, for four-channel tape (1976) (H. 54), undated, 1 10 inch reel; speed unknown; Computer output Original recordings from computer output. Contents: a. Golden mean glissandi (forward) - 5dB level; b. all instruments glissandi - 3dB level; c. Octave glissandi - 2dB level; d. "wedge" between steady state and glissandi; e. final combined steady state and "wedge"; f. heartbeat fantasy - original tape Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 200)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Metamorphosis, based on: Electronic sonata for 4-channel tape (H. 54), undated, 1 10 inch reel; 7 ½ ips, 2-channel stereo., tail out; Unique content? Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 201)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Midnight carnival, for a principal tape, indeterminate number of subsidiary tapes and other events in an urban environment (1976) (H. 55), undated, 1 5 inch reel; speed unknown; Alignment tape (special copy) Alignment Sheet with instructions included in tape container. Notes on container: Dubbings at 7 ½ ips of Ampex standard alignment tape 1. 4-channel a. all channels at 0dB b. channels A, B, C, D in that order 2. 2-channel a. all channels b. channels L, R in that order Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 202)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Midnight carnival, for a principal tape, indeterminate number of subsidiary tapes and other events in an urban environment (1976) (H. 55), undated, 1 7 inch reel; speed unknown; Duplicate of Tape 205 BHAM collage only Tape digitally reformatted: No (Item 203)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Midnight carnival, for a principal tape, indeterminate number of subsidiary tapes and other events in an urban environment (1976) (H. 55), undated, 1 10 inch reel; 15 ips, 4-channel quadraphonic, Tail out; 4-channel Master tape Master quadraphonic BHAM collage Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 204)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Midnight carnival, for a principal tape, indeterminate number of subsidiary tapes and other events in an urban environment (1976) (H. 55), undated, 1 10 inch reel; 15 ips, 2-channel stereo.; Stereo Master Master 2-channel tape BHAM collage Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 205)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Midnight carnival, for a principal tape, indeterminate number of subsidiary tapes and other events in an urban environment (1976) (H. 55), undated, 1 10 inch reel; 7 ½ ips, 4-channel quadraphonic, on 1.5 mil, ½" tape, Ampex 406; Tail out; Performance tapes No. 1-4 Performance Tape No. 1: a. Electronic Sonata Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 206)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Midnight carnival, for a principal tape, indeterminate number of subsidiary tapes and other events in an urban environment (1976) (H. 55), undated, 1 10 inch reel; 7 ½ ips, 4-channel quadraphonic, on 1.5 mil, ½" tape, Ampex 406; Tail out; Performance tapes No. 1-4 Performance Tape No. 2: a. Electronic Sonata Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 207)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Midnight carnival, for a principal tape, indeterminate number of subsidiary tapes and other events in an urban environment (1976) (H. 55), undated, 1 10 inch reel; 7 ½ ips, 4-channel quadraphonic, on 1.5 mil, ½" tape, Ampex 406; Tail out; Performance tapes No. 1-4 Performance Tape No. 3: a. BHAM collage; b. Portfolio tape Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 208)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Midnight carnival, for a principal tape, indeterminate number of subsidiary tapes and other events in an urban environment (1976) (H. 55), undated, 1 10 inch reel; 7 ½ ips, 4-channel quadraphonic, on 1.5 mil, ½" tape, Ampex 406; Tail out; Performance tapes No. 1-4 Performance Tape No. 4: a. Portfolio tape; b. BHAM collage Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 209)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Midnight carnival, for a principal tape, indeterminate number of subsidiary tapes and other events in an urban environment (1976) (H. 55), undated, 1 10 inch reel; 7 ½ ips, 2-channel stereo., Ampex 407 - 1 mil; Performance tapes No. 5-6 Performance Tape No. 5: a. Electronic Sonata; b. BHAM collage Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 210)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Midnight carnival, for a principal tape, indeterminate number of subsidiary tapes and other events in an urban environment (1976) (H. 55), undated, 1 10 inch reel; 7 ½ ips, 2-channel stereo., Ampex 407 - 1 mil; Performance tapes No. 5-6 Performance Tape No. 6: a. Electronic Sonata; b. Portfolio Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 211)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Midnight carnival, for a principal tape, indeterminate number of subsidiary tapes and other events in an urban environment (1976) (H. 55), undated, 1 10 inch reel; 7 ½ ips, 2-channel stereo., Tail out; Performance tape No. 7 "Two-channel, 1/4" version" a. BHAM collage - copy no. 2; b. Portfolio tape - copy no. 2 Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 212)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Midnight carnival, for a principal tape, indeterminate number of subsidiary tapes and other events in an urban environment (1976) (H. 55), undated, 1 10 inch reel; 7 ½ ips, 4-channel quadraphonic, Tail out; Performance tape No. 10 "Four-channel 1/4" version" a. BHAM collage - copy 1; b. BHAM collage - copy 2 Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 213)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Persiflage, for flute, oboe and percussion (1977) (H. 56), undated, 1 7 inch reel; speed unknown; Duplicate of Tapes 215 and 189 Performers: H. 53: Buffalo Philharmonic Orchestra conducted by Michael Tilson Thomas H. 56: Robert Dick, flute, Nora Post, oboe; Jan Williams, percussion Duration: 9:55 (H. 53); 10:40 (H. 56) Tape digitally reformatted: No (Item 214)
  H. 53, A preview of coming attractions, for symphony orchestra (1975) - abridged version
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Persiflage, for flute, oboe and percussion (1977) (H. 56), H. 56 recorded May 4, 1979; H. 58 recorded October 22, 1978, 1 10 inch reel; 15 ips, 2-channel stereo., Dolby A stretched; Master tapes Performers: H. 56: Robert Dick, flute; Nora Post, oboe, Jan Williams, percussion H. 58: Frances-Marie Uitti, diabelsie skrzypce; Yvar Mikhashoff, harpsichord H. 59: Laurence Trott, piccolo; Jan Williams, berimbau Duration: 10:40 (H. 56); 11:52 (H. 58); 12:15 (H. 59) Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 215)
  H. 58, Diabelskie skrzypce, for stringed instruments and harpsichord (1978)
  H. 59, An apotheosis of archaepterix, for piccolo and berimbau (1979)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Ponteach, a melodrama for narrator and piano (1977) (H. 57), Recorded December 1, 1977 premiere, 1 7 inch reel; speed unknown; Performers: Paul Schmidt, narrator; Yvar Mikhashoff, piano Duration: 26:54 Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 216)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Ponteach, a melodrama for narrator and piano (1977) (H. 57), undated, 1 10 inch reel; speed unknown; Storage tapes Duplicate of Tapes 216 and 223 Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 217)
  H. 61, Minuet and trio, for six performers (1980)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Diabelskie skrzypce, for stringed instruments and harpsichord (1978) (H. 58), H. 58 recorded on February 4, 1982, 1 7 inch reel; speed unknown; Different performances Performers: H. 58: Frances-Marie Uitti, diabelskie skrzypce (2nd performance on cello); Yvar Mikhashoff, harpsichord (2nd performance piano) H. 59: Laurence Trott, piccolo; Jan Williams, berimbau Duration: 11:52, 9:25 (H. 58, 1st and 2nd performance); 12:16 (H. 59) Two performances of "Diabelskie skrzypce" with same performers. Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 218)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Diabelskie skrzypce, for stringed instruments and harpsichord (1978) (H. 58), H. 62 recorded September 21, 1982, 1 10 inch reel; 15 ips, 2-channel stereo, Dolby A, Tail out; Possibly different performances - durations differ Performers: H. 62: Yvar Mikhashoff, piano H. 58: Frances-Marie Uitti, diabelskie skrzypce; Yvar Mikhashoff, harpsichord Duration: 20:28 (H. 62); 12:04 (H. 58) Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 219)
  H. 62, Quadrilateral, for piano and tape (1981)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 String quartet No. 7 (1979) I. Allegro Moderato (H. 60), undated, 1 7 inch reel; 7 ½ ips, 2-channel stereo.; Duplicate of Tape 221 Duration: 26:00 Tape digitally reformatted: No (Item 220)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 String quartet No. 7 (1979) (H. 60), Recorded June 27, 1981, 1 10 inch reel; 15 ips, 2-channel stereo., Dolby A, tail out; Master tape Performers: Kronos String Quartet Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 221)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 String quartet No. 7 (1979) (H. 60), Recorded June 28, 1981, 1 10 inch reel; 15 ips, 2-channel stereo., Dolby A, (Ampex 406); Tail out; Disk Submaster Disk submaster; different recording date from Tape 221 - error or different performance? Performers: Kronos String Quartet Duration: 26:00 Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 222)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Minuet and trio, for six performers (1980) (H. 61), undated, 1 7 inch reel; speed unknown; H. 61 duplicated on Tape 217 Performers: H. 61: Martha Herr, John Boudler, Gregory Piontek, Laurence Trott, Yvar Mikhashoff, Lejaren Hiller; H. 62: Yvar Mikhashoff, piano Duration: 9:02 (H. 61); 20:26 (H. 62) Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 223)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Quadrilateral, for piano and tape (1981) (H. 62), Recorded September 21, 1982, 1 10 inch reel; 15 ips, 4-channel quadraphonic, DBX, Tail out; Master tape Performers: Yvar Mikhashoff, piano Duration: 20:25 Notes on container: Channel 1 - Tape L; Channel 2 - Piano L ? L in stereo Channel 3 - Piano R; Channel 4 - Tape R ? R in stereo Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 224)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Quadrilateral, for piano and tape (1981) (H. 62), Recorded September 21, 1982, 1 10 inch reel; 15 ips, 2-channel stereo., Dolby A, Tail out; Submaster tape with master tapes of tape cues Performers: Yvar Mikhashoff, piano Duration: 20:14 Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 225)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Quadrilateral, for piano and tape (1981) (H. 62), undated, 1 10 inch reel; 15 ips, 2-channel stereo., Dolby A, Tail out; Piano tape master Performers: Yvar Mikhashoff, piano Duration: ca 16:08 Original piano recording Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 226)
  I. Book 1 4:04 II. Book 2 4:03 III. Book 3 3:54 IV. Book 4 4:07
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Quadrilateral, for piano and tape (1981) (H. 62), undated, 1 10 inch reel; 15 ips, 2-channel stereo.; Cue tapes Duration: 11:54, 1:06, 10:09 (H. 64) H. 64: 1. Lembrança da Bahia; 2. Two micro studies; 3. Poetic Images H. 62: Cues 1-5 Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 227)
  H. 64, Three compositions for tape (1983)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Music for "Chang Fu, the witch of Moon Mountain", for soprano, flute, viola, harp and percussion, text by Webster Smalley (1982) (H. 63), undated, 1 7 inch reel; speed unknown; Cue tape Duplicate of Tape 231 Tape digitally reformatted: No (Item 228)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Music for "Chang Fu, the witch of Moon Mountain", for soprano, flute, viola, harp and percussion, text by Webster Smalley (1982) (H. 63), undated, 1 7 inch reel; speed unknown; Duplicate of Tape 230 Performers: Martha Herr, soprano; Laurence Trott, flute/piccolo; Diane Williams, viola; Mario Falcão, harp; John Boudler, percussion; Bruce Penner, conductor Duration: 29:12 Tape digitally reformatted: No (Item 229)
  I. Overture 3:11 II. Song of the Meadowlark 5:27 III. Harvest Song 3:02 IV. Lute Song 2:47 V. Song of Good Work 6:11 VI. Nighttime 2:30 VII. Finale 5:40
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Music for "Chang Fu, the witch of Moon Mountain", for soprano, flute, viola, harp and percussion, text by Webster Smalley (1982) (H. 63), Recorded September 21, 1982, 1 10 inch reel; 15 ips, 2-channel stereo., Dolby A, Tail out; Master tape Master performance Performers: Martha Herr, soprano; Laurence Trott, flute/piccolo; Diane Williams, viola; Mario Falcão, harp; John Boudler, percussion; Bruce Penner, conductor Duration: 31:04 Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 230)
  I. Overture 3:11 II. Song of the Meadowlark 5:27 III. Harvest Song 3:02 IV. Lute Song 2:47 V. Song of Good Work 6:11 VI. Nighttime 2:30 VII. Finale (without concert cuts) 7:32
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Music for "Chang Fu, the witch of Moon Mountain", for soprano, flute, viola, harp and percussion, text by Webster Smalley (1982) (H. 63), undated, 1 10 inch reel; 15 ips, 2-channel stereo., Dolby A, Tail out; Cue tape master Master cue tapes Duration: 31:04 Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 231)
  I. Overture 3:11 II. Song of the Meadowlark 5:27 III. Harvest Song 3:02 IV. Lute Song 2:47 V. Song of Good Work 6:11 VI. Nighttime 2:30 VII. Finale 7:32
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Three compositions for tape (1983) (H. 64), undated, 1 7 inch reel; speed unknown; Duration: 23:16 Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 232)
  I. Lembranca da Bahia 11:54 II. Two Microstudies 1:05 III. Poetic Images 10:02
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Tetrahedron, for harpsichord (1983) (H. 65), undated, 1 7 inch reel; speed unknown; Duplicate of Tape 234 Performers: H. 65: Michael McCandless, harpsichord Duration: 18:07 (H. 65); 3:48 (H. 66) H. 66: only 1st movement (Manierato e con Rubato) Tape digitally reformatted: No (Item 233)
  I. Overture 3:46 II. Minuet 3:28 III. Chaconne 8:15 IV. Gigue 2:26 + 0:08
  H. 66, Staircase tango, for piano (1984) I. Manierato e con Rubato 3:48
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Tetrahedron, for harpsichord (1983) (H. 65), undated, 1 10 inch reel; see note, 2-channel stereo., Dolby A; Master Performers: H. 65: Michael McCandless, harpsichord H. 66: Yvar Mikhashoff, piano Duration: 18:07 (H. 65) H. 65: Master tape; 15 ips; tail out H. 66: storage copy of concert performance; 7 ½ ips Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 234)
  I. 3:46 II. 3:28 III. 8:15 IV. 2:26
  H. 66, Staircase tango, for piano (1984)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Algorithms III, for nine instruments and tape (1984) (H. 67), undated, 1 7 inch reel; 7 ½ ips, 2-channel stereo., Tail out; Cue tape Cue tapes - unclear if all are duplicated on following tapes Contents: I. Refinements: Versions 1-4 II. Quotations and Phraseology: Versions 1-4 III. Synthesis: Versions 1-4 12" between versions, 6" between movements "Sequence on cue tape: version 1; version 2; version 3; version 4 (in that order)" Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 235)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Algorithms III, for nine instruments and tape (1984) (H. 67), undated, 1 10 inch reel; speed unknown, Dolby A,; Master of Cue tape Master cue tapes Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 236)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Algorithms III, for nine instruments and tape (1984) (H. 67), undated, 1 10 inch reel; speed unknown, 2-channel stereo., Dolby A; Cue tape master Master cue tapes Contents: 1st movement: versions 1-4 2nd movement: versions 1-4 3rd movement: versions 1-4 Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 237)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Algorithms III, for nine instruments and tape (1984) (H. 67), undated, 1 10 inch reel; 15 ips, mono.; Mono masters/Mono cue tape master Master mono cue tapes Movement 1 Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 238)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Algorithms III, for nine instruments and tape (1984) (H. 67), undated, 1 10 inch reel; 15 ips, mono.; Mono masters/Mono cue tape master Master mono cue tapes Movements 2 and 3 Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 239)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Algorithms Cycle (H. 42, 48, 67), undated, 1 7 inch reel; speed unknown; Version 1 Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 240)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Algorithms Cycle (H. 42, 48, 67), undated, 1 7 inch reel; speed unknown; Version 2 Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 241)
  Algorithms I: (1) The Decay of Information (2) Icosahedron (3) The Incorporation of Constraints Algorithms II: (1) Canpanology Algorithms III: (1) Refinements (2) Quotations and Phraseology (3) Synthesis
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Algorithms Cycle (H. 42, 48, 67), undated, 1 7 inch reel; speed unknown; Version 3 Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 242)